KAT VANE TEMPEST
201/1 Brunswick Road
Brunswick East Vic 3057
p. 0423 599 909 e. katvanetempest@gmail.com

Kat has more than 10 years' experience within the cultural not-for-profit and government agency sectors, providing high-level expertise in strategic and operational planning, stakeholder management and business devolvement. Kat has worked with some of Australia's most iconic cultural offers including the Australian Centre for the Moving Image (ACMI), the Australian Centre for Contemporary Art (ACCA), Experimenta Media Arts and most recently Multicultural Arts Victoria. Kat is currently under the mentorship of the Australia Council for the Arts and Creative Partnerships Australia in partnership with McCarthy Mentoring.

EDUCATION

2009 Master of Arts (Arts Management), RMIT

2007 Bachelor of Arts (Arts History), Griffith University

RECENT EMPLOYMENT HISTORY
October 2012 – Present
MULTICULTURAL ARTS VICTORIA
Philanthropy and Fundraising Officer
Reporting to the CEO

Multicultural Arts Victoria is Victoria's peak arts organisation for the promotion of cultural diversity in the arts. MAV represents artists and communities from culturally and linguistically diverse backgrounds and collaborates with a range of key arts organisations in the state to take a leadership role for the advancement of multicultural arts at a local, national and international level.

Areas of responsibility include: overall planning, procurement, development and management of corporate sponsorships, private donors, and philanthropic trusts and foundations.

Key achievements in this role: election commitment from the incoming State Labor Government, triennial funding from the Scanlon Foundation, significant bequest for the organisation (\$350,000), Commonwealth Bank of Australia sponsorship, successful tender for the redevelopment of Princes Pier and the retention and growth of MAV's supporter network.

April 2009 – June 2011 EXPERIMENTA MEDIA ARTS Communications and Development Manager Reporting to the Director

Experimenta Media Arts develops and supports media artists and their practice through a biennial exhibition, commissioning program and national and international touring. Experimenta promotes media art to Australian audiences and provides development and mentoring for regional galleries.

Areas of responsibility included: business development, marketing and audience development, market development (international consultancies), branding and all marketing and communication outputs.

Key achievements in this role: successfully attracted more financial support within the first year from private donors and philanthropic trusts and foundations than the organization had ever previously achieved. Successfully rebranded the organization's key offer growing audience attendances by over 200%.

September 2008 – April 2009
AUSTRALIAN CENTRE FOR CONTEMPORARY ART (ACCA)
Market Development Coordinator
Reporting to the Executive Director

Australian Centre for Contemporary Art (ACCA) is a premier Victorian contemporary arts space, presenting an annual season of free public exhibitions, an educational program and professional development opportunities for professional artists.

Areas of responsibility included: researching/profiling possible supporter prospects and implementing plans for engagement, negotiating, executing and servicing partnership agreements for all cash and in-kind sponsors, preparing funding applications, producing sponsorship kits, proposals and contracts, and planning and delivering ACCA's events and hospitality program including sponsor events.

Key Achievements in this role: Securing new support and adding value to existing relationships. The timely delivery of sponsor benefits, contracts and partnership acquittals.

May 2007 – September 2008
AUSTRALIAN CENTRE FOR THE MOVING IMAGE (ACMI)
Development and Partnerships Administrator
Reporting to the Development and Partnerships Director

Australian Centre for the Moving Image (ACMI) is the agency responsible for the operation and programming as well as development and research at the Australian Centre for the Moving Image. The centre is Australia's only venue dedicated to screen culture and creates and exhibits the moving image in many forms. ACMI also gives the public access to its collections, conducts research and hosts education activities.

Areas of responsibility included: supporting the Director and wider Development Team with submitting funding applications and delivering key sponsor/stakeholder events.

Key Achievements in this role: the timely and effective management of both internal and external stakeholder relationships and events.

BOARDS

2013 – Current

Director of SEVENTH Gallery (ARI, Fitzroy, Melbourne)

GRANTS

2014 Australia Council for the Arts, Creative Partnerships Australia and McCarthy Mentoring - Philanthropic Mentoring Program

ADDITIONAL

2011 – Current

Regular guest lecturer in at RMIT in Arts Management (Master of Arts)

RECENT CONFERENCES AND INDUSTRY EVENTS

Curated and presented a media art screening program at the 2010 World Expo in Shanghai. Over 8 million visitors to the pavilion saw this program. Attended and participated in the Victoria Week celebrations at the Australia Pavilion, World Expo, Shanghai as a member of the Multimedia Victoria (MMV) ICT representative group hosted by then Premier John Brumby and attended by leading Australian and Chinese ICT business leaders.

Presented a paper on audience development at the A3 Asia Art Award Forum in Seoul at which arts industry leaders from around the world came together to discuss the relationship between contemporary art and the changes in culture and society that followed the development of digital technology.

Curated and presented an interactive media art exhibition at the Creative Industries Week in Shanghai, supported by Austrade. Over 70,000 visitors to the event attended this exhibition.

Recent publications include articles in the NAVA Quarterly and Artlink.

References available upon request.